这是二零二四年普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意回答。
听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
Yes, certainly. Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kind of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Wow, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
OK, well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form and
some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
Let's part. Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话，
每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完。
每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间。
看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有。
五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间。
to read the first part of part.
Did you watch the talent show on TV last night?
No, I missed it.
I went with my mom to buy some clothes.
I love this park.
It's so beautiful.
It surely is.
Are you tired?
Shall we stop by the lake for a few minutes?
Good idea. Let's go to that cafe for a little refreshment.
Tom, shall we invite the Smiths around for dinner this Sunday?
Sure, but I need to pack for Monday's business trip.
What about Saturday?
OK. Barbara, do you want to play table tennis with us tonight?
I'd love to, but I can't.
I'm catching the last train to Denver to see my grandma.
I need to take her to visit a doctor tomorrow morning.
Alex, did you feed the cat this morning?
I don't think she can wait.
Alright, after I this chapter, I just can't let go of this book.
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。
每。
段对话或独白后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
three A, B, and After listening, each will seconds seconds answer.
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间
阅读各个小题。
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话。
回答第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
Miss, do you need any help?
I want to get fit, but exercise doesn't seem to help.
What kind of exercise have you done before?
I did jogging now and then, but it was so boring, so I changed to weightlifting.
But it was so demanding, and I was afraid of getting injured, so I went bike riding.
Oh, I see.
You need to be consistent.
I suggest you do different kinds of on one day or on different days of the week.
This will help hold your interest, so you can keep coming back.
Miss, do you need any help?
I want to get fit, but exercise doesn't seem to help.
What kind of exercise have you done before?
I did jogging now and then, but it was so boring, so I changed to weightlifting.
But it was so demanding, and I was afraid of getting injured, so I went bike riding.
Oh, I see.
You need to be consistent.
I suggest you do different kinds of exercise on one day or on different days of the
week. This will help hold your interest, so you can keep coming back.
听下面一段对话。
回答第八至第十三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Thank you listening!
Hello? Brown's Grill?
How may I help you?
Hi. I'd like to book a table for Friday evening.
Okay. How many people are there in your party?
There will be six.
And what time would you like to come?
Let's say at 6.30.
I'm afraid we don't have anything available then.
We could seat you at 5.30 or 8 o
Oh, 8 o is better.
Fine. May I have your name?
Yes. It's Anderson.
Thank you. We'll see you on Friday.
By the way, we've moved to Howard Street.
Oh, yeah. I know.
Thanks. Hello? Brown's Grill?
How may I help you?
Hi. I'd like to book a table for Friday evening.
Okay. How many people are there in your party?
There will be six.
And what time would you like to come?
Let's say at 6.30.
I'm afraid we don't have anything available then.
We could seat you at 5.30 or 8 o Oh, 8 o is better.
Fine. May I have your name?
Yes. It's Anderson.
Thank you. We'll see you on Friday.
By the way, we've moved to Howard Street.
Oh, yeah. I know.
Thanks. Jacob, do you have a minute now?
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒。
中的时间阅读这三个小题
Sure. it's not easy to say, but I have to tell you, you're not in our group.
For the class project.
Sarah, what do you mean?
You know I'm always in a group with you.
I know. It's just that this time,
this time we made the group differently.
And because you were late,
we've already made the group.
See? There are four of us already.
So? We can't be a group of
Well, Professor North said there should be no more than four people in each group.
It's not about you or your work or anything like that.
Okay. But please count me in next time.
Jacob, do you have a minute now?
Sure. Well, it's not easy to say, but I have to tell you, you're not in our group.
For the class project.
Sarah, what do you mean?
You know I'm always in a group with you.
I know. It's just that this time,
this time we made the group differently.
And because you were late,
we've already made the group.
See? There are four of us already.
So? We can't be a group of
Well, Professor North said there should be no more than four people in each group.
It's not about you or your work or anything like that.
Okay. But please count me in next time.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十六
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读着。
三个小题。
There is a music concert in Victoria Park at four o Do you want to go?
Yes. Professor Darwin's lecture is cancelled.
I'm free this evening.
Great. The band plays pretty good music.
For the last three years I have never missed it.
How long ago did the band start playing in the park?
I think it was five years ago.
Every year they arrive the first week of and play for a week.
You're sure to enjoy this evening.
There will be good country music.
My favorite is rock and roll, but I have to say that country music can be quite
beautiful sometimes.
I like all kinds of music, especially jazz.
Oh, Janie, we have to go now.
Why? There's plenty of time.
Many people are heading to the park.
The traffic will be terrible.
Alright. But I have to return these books first.
Okay. I'll be waiting for you at the bus station.
Hey, Janie. Where are you going?
To the library.
There is a music concert in Victoria Park at four o Do you want to go?
Yes. Professor Darwin's lecture is cancelled.
I'm free this evening.
Great. The band plays pretty good music.
For the last three years I have never missed it.
How long ago did the band start playing in the park?
I think it was five years ago.
Every year they arrive the first week of July and play for a week.
You're sure to enjoy this evening.
There will be good country music.
My favorite is rock and roll, but I have to say that country music can be quite
beautiful sometimes. I like all kinds of music, especially jazz.
Oh, Janie, we have to go now.
Why? There's plenty of time.
Many people are heading to the park.
The traffic will be terrible.
Alright. But I have to return these books first.
Okay. I'll be waiting for you at the bus station.
听下面一段独白，回答第十七至第二十四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小题。
Good morning, everyone.
This lesson is a part of our leadership series.
Let me start by sharing a story of Richard Rochester, one of the most successful
businessmen in Britain.
Years ago, I was given the task of organizing a conference in the south of England.
I chose a five -star hotel owned by Rochester as the venue.
Susan, the receptionist, helped me arrange everything perfectly.
Once when we were chatting, I asked Susan if she'd ever met Mr.
Rochester. She said yes.
Shortly after Mr.
Rochester bought the hotel, he made an appointment to see the hotel manager.
When he arrived, the first person he met was Susan, who was cleaning the carpet.
He chatted with Susan for 30 minutes before keeping his appointment with the
manager. He spent all day at the hotel, talking with each member of the staff, from
the top guy to the lady who cleaned the toilets.
Six months later, Mr.
Rochester paid another visit.
Susan had been promoted to receptionist, but he recognized her immediately and
addressed her by name.
He even remembered that she had a little girl and what her name was.
Now, I don't believe that Richard Rochester has that good a memory.
He must have written a lot of notes after his first visit and read them over again
before that second visit.
It's time -consuming, but it shows the importance he places on human relationships.
I think that's one of the secrets of his success.
Good morning, everyone.
This lesson is a part of our leadership series.
Let me start by sharing a story of Richard Rochester, one of the most successful
businessmen in Britain.
Years ago, I was given the task of organizing a conference in the south of England.
I chose a five -star hotel, owned by Rochester, as the venue.
Susan, the receptionist, helped me arrange everything perfectly.
Once when we were chatting, I asked Susan if she'd ever met Mr.
Rochester. She said yes.
Shortly after Mr.
Rochester bought the hotel, he made an appointment to see the hotel manager.
When he arrived, the first person he met was Susan, who was cleaning the carpet.
He chatted with Susan for 30 minutes before keeping his appointment with the
manager. He spent all day at the hotel, talking with each member of the staff, from
the top guy to the lady who cleaned the toilets.
Six months later, Mr.
Rochester paid another visit.
Susan had been promoted to receptionist, but he recognized her immediately and
addressed her by name.
He even remembered that she had a little girl and what her name was.
Now, I don't believe that Richard Rochester has that good a memory.
He must have written a lot of notes after his first visit, and read them over again
before that second visit.
It's time -consuming, but it shows the importance he places on human relationships.
I think that's one of secrets of his success.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间。
将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
听力部分到此结束。